http://www.jennycraig.com/privacy

Skip to main content
Privacy
General
Many of the ways in which you interact with the Jenny Craig Web site (www.jennycraig.com and www.jennycraig.ca) (each, a “Site”) and the Jenny Craig mobile app (the “App”) allow us to learn about you. This Privacy Statement describes the type of information we collect from you when you visit our Site,
use our App, or become a Jenny Craig member and explains how Jenny Craig may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.
Information Collection
Information You Provide
Jenny Craig collects information from you when you choose to share it with us to use our Site or App, become a Jenny Craig member, create an online account with us, request information from us, sign up for newsletters or our email list, post in our chat rooms or message boards, or otherwise contact us. The categories of information we collect are your name, physical address, email address, telephone number, photo/image, gender, date of birth, health information such as your current weight and goal weight, food consumption, and measurements, and, if you are a Jenny Craig customer, a credit/debit card number or other financial information including information about your purchases from us, as well as your Jenny ID which is assigned upon membership. If you access your account through our website, or if you use our App, we collect your user name and password. In addition, if you allow the App to have your location data, that data is only used to help you identify the nearest Jenny Craig Center. It is not stored. You have the option of choosing whether or not to reveal some personally identifiable information to us. If you do not provide all “required” information, however, some portions of our Site, App, or membership features will not work properly for you, or you will not be able to register or access certain sections of the Site. In the event of a complaint, we may also receive personally identifiable information about you from other parties or from other users or third parties who may communicate information to us about you in relation to that complaint.
Information Automatically Collected
We may use cookies, web beacons, log files, or other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to and users of our Sites and App, to deliver online advertisements that we think would be more relevant to your interests, and to monitor interactions with our emails and online advertisements. For example, we may automatically collect certain information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, software version, and the domain name from which you accessed the Site or App. In addition, we may collect information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the Site or App, the areas or pages of the Site or App that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing or using the Site or App, the number of times you return to the Site, other click-stream or Site or App usage data, and emails or ads that you open, forward or click-through to our Site or App.
Please note that our Sites use Google Analytics, a service that transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or visitors, nor does it associate users’ or visitors’ IP addresses with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage. In addition, we use Flurry, another analytics tool, to track statistics about downloads, frequency of use of our App, ratings, and similar metrics. Flurry does not collect your personally identifiable information.
Cookies and Other Tracking Methods
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your hard drive when you visit our Site. We use cookies or, in a limited number of cases, IP addresses or other tracking tools, for a number of reasons. For example, these tools may (a) allow you to store your password without having to constantly re-enter it; (b) help us to tailor our Site or a marketing message to better match your needs and interests; and (c) allow us to better understand how you and others use our Site, which in turn helps us focus our resources on features that are the most popular. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but some parts of our Site may not work properly if you do. Check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to know your choices about not having this information used by certain Service Providers (defined below), please click here.
“Do-Not-Track” (“DNT”) is an optional browser setting that allows you to express your preferences regarding tracking by advertisers and other third-parties. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, ad networks, plug-in providers, and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity via cookies or other tracking technologies. We do not currently respond to Do-Not-Track browser signals or mechanisms. See the privacy policies of any linked sites with respect to how they respond to DNT signals, as their policies may differ from our own.
Information from Other Sources
Information Use
Jenny Craig may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:
To operate our Site and App;
To enhance our Site and App;
To deliver customized Site and App content, targeted offers and advertising on the Site or App, on other sites or apps, or via email;
To analyze our Site or App traffic and optimize how we lay out content on the Site or App;
To fulfill orders, provide service and communicate with customers;
To research and develop new products or services;
To post reviews of products and services our Site or App;
To respond to your inquiries;
To contact you with information, newsletters, and promotional materials from Jenny Craig;
To contact you when necessary;
To review the usage and operations of our Site or App and improve our content, products, and services;
To address problems with the Site, App, or our business;
To promote the Site or App;
To manage our telecommunications networks;
To protect the security or integrity of the Site, App, and our business;
As described to you at the point of data collection; and
To use and disclose your credit/debit card information only to process payments and prevent fraud.
We may combine the information you provide to us with information (1) from and about you that we automatically collect when you use Jenny Craig’s Sites or App, (2) we collect when you visit a Jenny Craig Center, or (3) from other online and offline sources in an effort to provide you with a seamless experience, better serve your needs, and provide you with content and advertising that is more relevant to your interests.
Information Disclosure/Sharing
Jenny Craig may also disclose the personal information we collect from and about you as follows: (1) to our Service Providers, if the disclosure will enable them to perform a business, professional or technical support function for us; (2) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of the Jenny Craig Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party; (3) to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement or regulatory agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; (4) as described to you at the point of collection; (5) to third parties who provide educational content regarding weight loss and health; and (6) in the context of a sale of our assets or business as described below.
Jenny Craig may share aggregate, deidentified information with third parties for our business purposes.
Jenny Craig may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through this Site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.
Security
We take physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the confidentiality of the information we collect from and about our customers and Site visitors. Although your privacy is important to us, we cannot guarantee our security measures. Jenny Craig encourages you to learn as much as you can about your privacy on the Internet.
When you enter sensitive personal information (such as credit card information), we encrypt the transmission of that information using Secure Socket Layer technology (SSL).
Service Providers
Jenny Craig may contract with third parties to perform functions related to the Sites or App (“Service Providers”). Service Providers will have access to your information needed to perform their business functions, but may not use or share that information for other purposes. All companies with which we do business have agreed to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement and will not sell, rent, or otherwise transmit your personal information to third parties.
Public Forums & Reviews
Any information that you may disclose on our Sites or App such as in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on the Site or App, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas. If you terminate your account, we may continue to show some of your content in anonymized form.
Links to Other Websites
The Sites and App may have links to third-party websites or applications, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites or applications. Please note that if you provide any information on your own to third parties, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions before disclosing information to third parties.
Social Media Sharing Features
This website may offer social media sharing features or other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take on this website with other media, and vice versa.
These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you are visiting on our website, and they may set a cookie or employ other tracking technologies. The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party that provides the social sharing feature.
Social media sharing features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with those features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social media sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the third parties that provide these features.
Your California Privacy Rights
If you are a California resident, you have a right to request the following from companies conducting business in California:
The categories of personal information we have collected about you.
The categories of sources from which we have collected your personal information
The business or commercial purpose for which we collected or, if applicable, sold your personal information
The categories of third parties with whom we shared your personal information in the last 12 months.
The specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.
The categories of personal information that we have shared with third parties about you for a business purposes.
If applicable, the categories of personal information that we sold about you and the categories of third parties who received your personal information in the sale.
a list of all third-parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information, as defined under California Civil Code Section 1798.80(e), during the preceding year for third- party direct marketing purposes
We will respond to one request per California resident per calendar year, according to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, and two requests according to Sections 1798.110 and 1798.115. You may request this information
by contacting us by phone at 1-800-JennyCare (536-6922) or by email at dataprivacy@jennycraig.com. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. Please allow up to forty-five (45) days for a response.
We do not provide or share personal data to third parties for money.
We do share personal information with companies that we partner with, including to help us market or advertise to you. When this information is in a format that directly identifies you by name, it is typically not shared with any other companies for third-party marketing or advertising purposes. More information on this can be found above in the Information Use section.
Even though we do not provide personal information to any third parties for money, the California Civil Code’s definition of “sale” includes disclosure of personal information for monetary or “other consideration.”
Therefore the law may characterize our providing the following categories of information we share with our service providers, such as personalizing your experience with us or helping us to market or advertise our products and services to you, as "sales" of personal information:Identifiers and contact information, and
Purchase or other commercial information.
You have the right to direct us to not sell your personal information to third-parties by clicking on the following link: DO NOT SELL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION
Jenny Craig may continue to collect and share personal information about you with our third party service providers as described herein as long as the sharing does not constitute a "sale" of personal information under California law, such as continuing to provide services to you. When you adjust your settings through the link above, you will only opt out of the "selling" activity on the browser, device, and website you are using when you tap the Confirm button.
You also have the right to request that we delete your personal information. Once we receive your request, we will let you know what, if any, personal information we can delete from our records, and we will direct any service providers with whom we shared your personal information to also delete your personal information from their records. There may be circumstance where we cannot delete your personal information or direct service providers to delete your personal information from their records. For example, if we need to (1) retain your personal information to complete a transaction or provide a good or service; (2) detect security incidents; (3) protect against unlawful activities; (4) identify, debug, or repair errors; or (5) comply with a legal obligation.
Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy
Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Sites or App to, nor do we knowingly, collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen. If we discover that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information without verifiable parental consent, we will delete that information. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 years old and you believe we have received personal information from your child, please contact us at jennycare@jennycraig.com to request deletion of that information.
Who May Use This Website
This website is designed for users from the United States and Canada. Users from other countries are advised not to disclose personal information unless such users consent to and agree to have their information used as set forth in this Privacy Policy, rather than under the laws of their home country. You should not submit any personal information via this website unless you consent to and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and by United States and California law.
Access to Your Personal Information
You may sign into your account, e-mail us at dataprivacy@jenncraig.com
or contact Customer Service (see “If You Have Questions”, below) or your Jenny Craig Anywhere Representative to update your profile information stored by Jenny Craig or request for data to be deleted.
Updates
Jenny Craig reserves the right to revise this Privacy Statement at any time, and may apply any changes to information previously collected, as permitted by law. If we change the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will provide notice to you by posting the updated Privacy Statement on our Site and App, updating the effective date to reflect that changes have been made. Your continued use of our Sites or App following any such change constitutes your agreement to follow and be bound by the terms as changed.
If You Have Questions
If you have questions about this Privacy Statement or the practices described herein, you may contact us at 1-800-JennyCare (536-6922).
Effective Date: September 15, 2020
×
Authentication
Close
